hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation playlist now
continuing with our topic on test
automation obstacles let's look at the
next obstacle which is called the
extracting text now in this particular
obstacle we need to automate a test step
where we need to take the total amount
which is shown in the success message uh
which is here right and then uh we need
to enter that uh amount into this
particular text box okay so if I enter
this particular amount
here okay and then you will see that
this obstacle is completed so this is
all we need to do here right now the
challenge here obviously is uh this
particular text is dynamic which means
the amount keeps on changing right right
so you need to be able to extract this
particular amount from this Dynamic text
and then you need to enter it into the
text box so let's see how we can do this
uh in
tosa okay so uh coming back to our tosa
and here uh let's go to our obstacles
and here I am going to now uh scan this
particular application
right
okay so here um I can see the total
amount text box but I cannot see uh this
success message right so I'm going to
increase the filtered items so that I
can see uh some of the underlying
elements here okay and this is the text
uh which contains the purchase completed
and then the total amount right and then
uh I need to also select the text box
okay so these are the two elements which
I
want and then uh we are going to call
this success
message okay and we are going to call
the module but we will copy this
obstacle
here and we'll paste it here okay and
then I'm going to save this and close
the scan right so our module is created
now uh let's go to our test cases
section and here we are going to create
a new test
case uh again with the same obstacle uh
ID and then let's go ahead and add the
module to this test case right so we
have got uh a Dev element which contains
the text and then we have got a textt
box right now uh we need to extract the
amount from the text and that amount is
dynamic so it keeps on changing right so
the only way I can think of is we can
buffer that particular amount right but
uh we cannot simply buffer uh the
complete text right that text uh
contains that Dynamic element so in this
case uh we have to use something called
X buffer okay so using the X buffer uh
we can basically verify the dynamic text
as well as we can buffer that Dynamic
element which is part of that text okay
so let's see how we can do this now
before we do that uh we need to look at
this uh success message element okay so
if you look at the properties you will
see that the inner text actually
contains the complete text right so it
contains the amount and uh some of other
text okay so we can use this inner text
property to extract this complete text
and from there we will try to extract
the amount okay so let's go back here
and
then here um I'm going to use the inner
text okay and then uh in this we are
going to call copy this particular text
but we are going to make it Dynamic okay
so I'm going to copy this
here and then uh we are going to remove
this I'm going to put a regular
expression
here okay and then uh because this
amount keeps on changing so I'm going to
buffer this and in this case I'm going
to use a x buffer Okay so uh we are
going to use
XB as you can see okay and then inside
this we are going to provide the buffer
name and I'm going to call it amount
okay and you'll also change the action
mode to verify okay so what this will do
is it will verify this Dynamic text and
also it will buffer this particular
amount okay uh into the amount buffer
name right now we can easily use that
particular buffer to enter it into this
particular text box okay so here I can
just use the buffer the normal buffer
and then I can call the amount
here
right so uh this is how you can extract
a piece of um text which is maybe
dynamic in nature uh from the complete
text using the X buffer so you can
buffer that particular uh text which you
want to buffer and then you can use that
buffered value uh to enter it into a
text box okay so this is how you can
solve this particular obstacle so let's
change the work state here and then
let's try and execute this and let's see
um if it can enter that particular
amount into the text
box okay so as you can see it was able
to extract the text and also it was able
to enter it into the text box right so
that completed our obstacle uh both the
tasks were completed right so it did the
verification here you can see and it was
also able to enter that particular
amount right so this is how uh you can
use x buffer and buffer to
basically um extract some Dynamic text
and also use that text uh at various
places in your test
cases that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video